# GITESH CHAUDHARI

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

giteshchaudhari6432@gmail.com | +91-7410722033 | hackerrank.com/Gitesh6432 | linkedin.com/in/Gitesh6432 | github.com/Gitesh6432 | leetcode.com/u/Gitesh6432

#### **SUMMARY**

An software developer with 4+ years of experience building applications using technologies like Python, Django, and cloud platforms like GCP and AWS. I'm comfortable with tools like GitHub, Jenkins, and Terraform, and have a strong foundation in data structures and algorithms.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python Programming Data Science Accessibility
Database Management Cloud Services Responsive Design

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

• Equifax Project - Open Banking

Jan 2023 - Present

- Advancement & Optimization of Bank-Scorecard System, achieving a +60% increase in operational efficiency.
- Implemented preventive maintenance strategies, resulting in a 20% decrease in equipment downtime.
- Executed GCP Alert and Mail Report Functionality for more than 60,000 customers has solely been developed, using Mailgun API and Request module

Nike Project

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

- Development of Airflow DAG's for Data Transfer Activities, streamline processes, Automation Systems.
- Advancement of the Nike-Tool module's UI using Django framework.
- Coordinated testing and validation, ensuring compliance with industry standards.
- Provided technical expertise, contributing to a 15% reduction in system failures.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **QR** code generator

Web Application to generate QR code from users data with customization feature i.e. colour, size and style.

#### Password generator

Generates strong meaningful passwords by utilizing information provided by the user.

# **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Engineering**

June 2016 - June 2020

Savitribai Phule Pune University

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi.

• Certifications: Python, Java, SQL & Problem Solving Skills Hackerrank Certifications

• Awards/Activities: Appreciation Certificate for Nike Project